# **Eric Paul**

multipurposegeek@gmail.com (971) 806-3088 http://multipurposegeek.com

Over a decade of experience developing client/server applications with Open Source tools, including Drupal, with an eye towards user experience, scalability, performance, and multi-API integration. Broad experience with a balanced spectrum of use cases, from one-off brochure sites, to multi-domain applications in the enterprise. Strong communicator, expert technical interpreter and adviser.

LinkedIn Eric GitHub mpgeek Twitter mpgeek Drupal mpgeek

### **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES & APIS	HTML5, PHP/Drupal, CSS/SASS, Javascript/jQuery, AJAX/AHAH, LAMP, Drush, Grunt/Node.js, Git, Behat/Mink/Cucumber, Web Services (REST, JSON), Bash/Shell scripting, LATEX
CONCEPTS	Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Test Driven Development (TDD), Continuous Integration (CI), User Experience, Responsive Implementation

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Phase2 Technology / OpenSourcery (Merger)

Senior Developer Mar 2013 - Nov 2015

Full-stack development for enterprise-class web software with Drupal and other Open Source tools in a high-volume production environment. Design and implement performant and scalable custom solutions including publishing workflows, translations, GIS/Mapping. Contrib project evaluation, selection, configuration, and extension; custom modules, migrations, deployments, and multiple-API integrations.

- Key frameworks: Migrate, Workbench/Workflow, i18n/Entity Translate, Leaflet/Geocluster, OpenAtrium, Salesforce, Views, Profile2, UUID, Features.
- Developer environment standardization with Grunt/Node scripting and virtual machine technologies.
- Continuous integration and automation with Git, Jenkins, Drush, Behat, and PHP Unit.

#### OakTree Digital

Developer Aug 2012 - Jan 2013

Full-stack Drupal application engineering: back-end development, site building, and theming, including responsive frontends. Contrib project evaluations, selection, configuration, and extension. Requirements extraction, implementation planning, and estimation. Client-facing technical advising.

■ Implemented a Single Sign On (SSO) integration with existing internal system for an enterprise client.

#### **Portland State University**

Themer, Developer Jun 2005 - Jul 2012

Web application development, testing, and maintenance, mostly in Drupal. Enterprise site building, theming, development and upgrade management for the University's main Drupal instance hosting a 200+ multisite.

 Worked on the team that implemented a platform-wide Drupal 6 to Drupal 7 migration for the multisite instance. Drush tooling and custom shell scripting.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Portland State University**

Jan 2002 - Jun 2008

Bachelor of Science - Electrical & Computer Engineering GPA: 3.23